

## ▶Juan Rodrigo Leaños Bermejo

e-Mail: rodrigo.bermejo@outlook.com www.rodrigobermejo.com LinkedIn



#### **Profile**

Being a qualified .NET and SharePoint consultant since 2010, I have several years of experience in Software Development, with special focus on collaboration and content management platforms, solution integration and business intelligence. During this period, I have also taken two Microsoft Certifications that ensure the technological accuracy. I'm particularly pleased to work with Microsoft technologies especially ASP.NET and C# and I'm always interested in new programming methods as well and innovative ways of doing things in a more efficient manner.

#### Education

# Strategic Information Systems Engineering, Aug 2006 - Aug 2010

- Polytechnic University of Aguascalientes (UPA).
- Specialist: Networking.

#### Work experience

- Portals and Collaboration Engineer, Definity First (Monterrey, Mexico) 05/2016 to: Date.
- Implemented multi-lingual web sites using site variation management system provided by Microsoft SharePoint Server 2016
- Created sites, built custom workflows, and managed permissions and content as requested from customers
- Implemented useful SharePoint capabilities out-of-the-box and complement with other libraries such as jQuery to create custom enhancements on current sites for customer satisfaction and efficiency
- Conducted formal and informal meetings with multiple groups to gathered requirements and provide solutions to existing problems
- Constructed multiple sub-sites, pages, and libraries with the deployment of the new SharePoint sites
- SharePoint Versions: 2010,2013,2016, Online.
- ▶ Software Engineer, Softtek (Aguascalientes, Mexico) 06/2015 to: 01/2016.
  - **IKA Systems.** Develop of new functionality and control change of different applications based in .NET, SQL Server and Oracle.
  - Conducted formal and informal meetings with multiple groups to gathered requirements and provide solutions to existing problems
  - Gathered and analyzed requirement from business
- SharePoint Consultant AXEN (Monterrey, Mexico) 10/2012 to: 06/2015.
  - Project The Home Depot Mexico | Intranet. Following Microsoft best practices for improve the existing SharePoint environment. The process involved the implementation of Newsgator (Sitrion) and Developed new SharePoint based business systems.

- Developed SharePoint assets such as Web Parts, Event Handlers, Application Pages, Workflows, aiming the improvement of existing SharePoint functionalities.
- Project in site AXEN. Developed SharePoint assets such as Web Parts, Event Handlers, Application Pages, Workflows, aiming the improvement of existing SharePoint functionalities.

## ▶ SharePoint Developer ISA (Aguascalientes, Mexico) 09/2010 - 08/2012

- Designed, Developed and Implemented Intranet systems based on the SharePoint 2007 platform, both WSS 3.0 and MOSS 2007.
- Developed new functionalities such as Web Parts, Event Handlers, Application Pages, Workflows, and other SharePoint assets aiming system environments based on Microsoft SharePoint 2007 and 2010.
- Performed both maintenance on existing SharePoint 2007 and 2010 applications and SharePoint 2007 to SharePoint 2010 migrations.
- Connected several different line of business applications to SharePoint using BDC, BCS, Web Services and custom development.
- Development of desktop applications in VB .NET & C#, Visual Fox Pro.

# Developer JR SATV (Aguascalientes, Mexico) 05/2009 - 09/2010

- Development of desktop applications in VB .NET & C#, Visual Fox Pro.
- Analysis, development and maintenance of databases SQL Server 2005, 2008
- Crystal Reports

## **Professional development**

- Certificación en fundamentos de .NET a universitarios | Desarroll@ Aguascalientes 2008 MCP 70-536 C#
- 5to. Simposio Latinoamericano de SharePoint | Microsoft México D.F. 2012
- Microsoft SharePoint 2010 Application development 070-573
- Microsoft Certification ID: 9009255

#### Skills and competences.

- Operative systems Windows: 98/XP/ Vista/7/8/Server 2003/Server 2008 R2.
- Operative systems Linux: Ubuntu V10+ Fedora V12+.
- Certification in Microsoft Office Specialist 2003 (Word, Excel, Power Point).
- Experience basic technical support to users.
- Programming basic level Java AWT/SWING.
- Programming basic level JSP/SERVLETS.
- Advanced programming C#, VB .NET.
- Advanced programming and design ASP y ASPX.
- Advanced programming and design PHP.
- Development and maintenance of databases for advanced level MySQL.
- Development and maintenance of databases for advanced level MS-SQL SERVER 2005, MS-SQL SERVER 2008 R2.
- Advanced programming TRANSACT-SQL.
- Installation and maintenance of SharePoint sites 2007, 2010, 2013.
- Crystal Reports.
- CISCO CCNA Modules 1, 2 y 3 and administration and configuration of wireless networks and VOIP.

#### **IDIOMAS**

- Spanish native,
- ▶ English good (80 %)